rewee.info 2015-09-05

# Privacy Policy - Linode

  1. Notice 

Linode, LLC (herein referred to as "Linode") collects and stores personal information, including the full name, company name (if applicable), billing address, credit card number and expiration date, email address, and source IP address for all customers. In some cases, photographic proof of identity and credit card credentials may be required prior to customer account activation. Inquiries regarding the collection and use of personal information may be made via email to [privacy@linode.com](mailto:privacy@linode.com), or via postal mail or facsimile using contact information found on our About Us page. 

  2. Security and Data Integrity 

Customer information is stored in electronic databases. Linode employs industry-standard technical safeguards, including but not necessarily limited to encryption of credit card information, password and/or cryptographic key-based authentication controls on servers which house personal information, browser-based SSL encryption, and other storage system access control mechanisms to protect the integrity of internal databases and prevent unauthorized access. Unless otherwise indicated by amendment to this privacy policy, in which case customers shall be notified and given the opportunity to exercise the "opt out" provisions discussed in this policy, personal information is stored only for use according to the purposes for which it was initially collected. 

  3. Third Party Disclosure 

Linode transfers personal information to third parties under the following normal business procedures: 

    1. Linode discloses the full name, billing address, and credit card account information of its customers to a third party merchant processing provider for billing purposes. Linode does not disclose customer information to other third parties except where required under applicable state and federal laws for purposes of investigation of criminal complaints, or where required by court order.
    2. Linode discloses the billing address, network IP address, and a partial credit card number (for issuing bank identification purposes) of customers to a third party as part of the sign-up process for fraud detection purposes.
  4. Access 

Customers have access to account-specific personal information stored about them via Linode's web-based interface for account management. Customers may update their information at any time. Customers who cancel their account may request that their personal information be deleted from Linode's databases, with the exception of: 

    1. network access logs, which may be stored for any duration of time at Linode's discretion,
    2. cases where financially fraudulent or otherwise illegal activity is deemed to have occurred (as determined by Linode management or law enforcement officials), in which case personal information may be retained indefinitely for purposes of ongoing investigation and prevention of fraud recurrence, or
    3. cases where a customer's violation of the Linode Terms of Service has resulted in cancellation of the customer's account (as defined by revocation of the customer's permission to utilize Linode's services), in which case personal information may be retained indefinitely for purposes of prevention of further use of Linode's services in the future by the offending individual. 
  5. Cookies 

We collect anonymous usage information on visitors to our site through use of [Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/analytics). This service may employ third party tracking cookies to gather anonymous browser, operating system, geographic, and web site navigation information. Use of our Linode Manager interface requires the acceptance of cookies for login session management purposes. 

  6. Unmanaged Service 

Customers bear sole responsibility for maintaining the security of virtual private server (VPS) environments maintained under their accounts. Customers are solely responsible for ensuring compliance with any and all applicable privacy guidelines and regulations for all jurisdictions in which they may operate with respect to appropriate practices for the collection, storage, and dissemination of personal information using their Linode VPS. In no event shall Linode be held liable for a customer's failure to adopt and/or practice appropriate measures for safeguarding personal information stored within or transmitted through their Linode VPS. 

  7. Opt Out Provision 

Customers shall have the right to opt out of any use of their personal information which is inconsistent with or beyond the scope of the purposes for which it was initially collected. In the event that, at Linode's discretion, service cannot be continued without customer acceptance of such modifications to the ways in which personal information is collected and/or used, customers who wish to opt out of such collection or use of their personal information will be notified and offered a pro-rated refund of any positive balance on their account with Linode. 

  8. Safe Harbor 

Linode complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Linode has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Linode's certification, please visit the [U.S. Department of Commerce's Safe Harbor](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/) web site. 

Linode, LLC has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by Linode, LLC, please visit the [BBB EU Safe Harbor Dispute Resolution Program](http://www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints) for more information and to file a complaint. 

  9. Enforcement 

Please direct compliance inquiries to [privacy@linode.com](mailto:privacy@linode.com). Third parties which may be contacted with compliance inquiries included the following: 

Council of Better Business Bureaus, Inc.  
BBB EU Safe Harbor Dispute Resolution Program  
[Online Contact Form](http://www.bbb.org/us/european-dispute-resolution/consumer/) U.S. Department of Commerce  
U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework  
1401 Constitution Avenue, N.W.  
Room 2003  
Washington, DC 20230  
Federal Trade Commission  
Consumer Response Center  
600 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW  
Washington, DC 20580 
  10. Changes 

Amendments to this privacy policy may be made at any time and you should check back frequently for any changes. Linode will never make changes to this policy that result in less protection of your personal information without sending notice. This policy was last updated on July 24, 2013.
